Shanuj Yadav

shanujyadav@gmail.com / +91 9528492010 / Bareilly, India

Summary

Skilled and dedicated Frontend Developer with 1.6 years of experience with a strong focus on building responsive, user friendly web and mobile applications using React and React Native. I have a deep understanding of JavaScript, TypeScript, and modern UI/UX principles. Proficient in integrating secure APIs, and managing state with Redux.

Experience

Software Developer

Altaneo Finance Pvt Ltd • Gurugram, India

05/2024 - Present

- Designed and developed scalable, secure web applications using modern frameworks such as Node.js, React, Redux js, and JavaScript, improving system performance and user experience.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams, including product managers and UX/UI designers, to gather requirements and translate them into efficient technical solutions.
- Built and integrated APIs to facilitate seamless communication between front-end and back-end systems, enhancing data flow and application responsiveness.

Software Developer

Neobyte Fintech Pvt. Ltd • Delhi , India

09/2023 - 12/2023

- Implemented robust encryption and decryption algorithms to secure sensitive data, ensuring confidentiality and integrity.
- Develop a multilingual website to reach a global audience with seamless content translation and localization.
- Developed and maintained dynamic, responsive websites and web applications using React js, and Redux js.
- Integrated secure RESTful APIs to enhance front-end functionality, ensuring seamless data flow and robust security protocols for optimal user experience

MERN Stack - React Native Intern

SSDN Technologies • Remote

03/2023 - 08/2023

- Worked on UI/UX improvements, enhancing the user interface with clean, modular, and responsive designs using React.is and React Native.
- Collaborated with senior developers using Agile methodologies, including daily stand-ups, sprint planning, and code reviews.
- Utilized Git for version control and collaborated with the team using GitHub to manage code changes and resolve conflicts.

Skills

React.js, React Native, Redux.js, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, Git, HTML, CSS, Typescript, AWS

Education

B.Tech - Computer Science

Dr. APJ Abdul Kalam Technical University • Bareilly, India

07/2023
Intermediate
SDIC • Puranpur, India
05/2019

High School

SDIC • Puranpur, India 05/2017

Languages

English, Hindi

Certificates

Web Development Fundamentals by IBM. (06/2023 - Present)